Now we will implement user sign in and the first thing you'll notice is that I have switched my database
to use my local moment.
So if you are using cloud you can continue using that otherwise you can switch to local database.
So let's go ahead and implement a user a in as well.
And the first thing you want to do is start with validators.
So let's go to what we have.
A sign of validator.
We can copy elements and then rename it let's call it sign in.
And while signing in we will require e-mail and password so we can get rid of the name.
And this is it.
We can save this and we can create a new route for you signing.
So let's go good roads of it's copy paste right here.
So it's going to be wrote a post method with signing and the value that we're going to use is signing.
And then the method we're gave to create is to sign it.
So let's import this one from the validated and we need to create this sign in control method.
Okay.
So let's go and create this site and control method.
And right here
exports signing request response to doing the signing process.
We need to perform a couple things.
The first one is we need to take.
If the user exists.
So if that doesn't exist then we can ask them to sign and sign up.
Next thing we need to authenticate.
So the users email and password submits.
So when we get the password from user we will compare that with the hacked version we have stored in
the database.
And if that met then we can authenticate.
And we already have the authenticate method.
They have already written here in the schema that we take the password.
And after that if all that is good then we can generate a decent web token
for this token will include the user I.D. and the secret that will be used.
So you'll see how it all works.
Let's begin with the check first.
First of all we want to grab the user email and password from request boy led to destruction from request
body
email and password and then we take user turn find one method we use this method and then we want to
find the user by email.
So we don't need to say like this because if the key value is same we can just leave it like so.
So email then we can use this execute method that concert mongers.
And here we can use a function so error or user.
So we will either get error or user.
So if there are no user.
So if there is error or no user then we can return the response with a status of 400 with annotation
and we can send the error message saying you know with that email does not exist.
Please sign up something like that.
Then we can try to authenticate it.
So let's move this year
so if not use your dot authenticate.
We passed the password to this password is a plain password that we get from the client.
So we give that password to this authenticate method we have in the User model and that will give us
either true or false I guess.
So if it is not true.
If the authentication failed then we want to again return the error response.
Let's copy and paste here.
And here we can write
email and password do not match.
Now if the user doesn't exist and authentication also passed then we can go ahead and generate the decent
web token and give to the client so that we can authenticate the user.
And to do that we need to first to bring in some Pegasus.
For example we have already installed the JWT I guess.
Let's bring that in second JWT equals to require the web token.
We also need the expanded W2 beggars so can't express to the beauty.
And this will help us take if the token has expired and if it is valid again so require the express
intent of the right.
Now before we generate the token we need to create a secret key so we can go to Ian Lee file and let's
write here.
The WG undisclosed secret.
And this can be anything.
Again just a random secret key that no one can guess.
Okay so I'm going to just type some letters and numbers.
It can be anything.
Write just so that people cannot guess it is secret and this secret will be used to generate this token.
Okay so let's create a variable called token and we're going to use this data to pageants use the same
method to create the same token I guess.
So here we're going to use idea user idea to create a token idea that's going to be user dot underscore.
So the user that we found in the database the one that is already registered to use it.
So we think that we use this idea to create a signed token as well as separate but come are we going
to use the secret key as well.
So process dirt envy dirt.
Did the beauty underscore secret.
And we also give the expiry date.
Okay.
So you can set expiry of one all one day or one week one month one year as long as you want again.
So let's do it for a day expire in let's say one day so this then we can create a signed token using
the user already dead over the secret and the expiry date.
Now we can set this token in the cookie as well.
So this start cookie with the name of token and the value is going to be this token.
I didn't know you said they expire here is worth expires in one day.
Then once we do all this we want to give the decent risk funds with the user information as well as
token so that our client whether to react or postman they can store that talk in some way and also store
the using permissions.
So next time when they make a request to our back end they can send that token and we can receive that
token and then we can validate that.
Yes the user is authenticate.
So let's just create a user object that we want to send a decent response.
So what do we want to send it.
We want to send the idea we want to send the user name name email and roll it out.
Okay.
So we want to send all this information off the user get a return response.
Jason
we give the token and we also give the user response.
Let's say now we can give this a try.
So let's go to postman and let's make a request to sign it again.
So we already have a user by the name of Ryan at G.M. dot com.
So the user is already here.
So let's try logging in.
Let's send this to sign in to make sure it is post to go to help us make sure we have the content type
application.
Jason is good to body.
Let's pick the raw data application Jason from you and we sent the email and password so that we can
log in
oh sorry.
Should be his DP.
All right let's try it.
Should be a s a missing s here is the second.
Let's save.
And let's give it a try.
And you see we get the token the decent web token as well as user information.
Beautiful but we do want to respond with hashed password and salt.
So what we can do here is we can come back here and the user let's send all this information instead
of the entire user that we got from the database.
Let's just send the user name name email in rural.
Okay let's say let's try one more time.
And this time we would get either a user name name email has been as token beautiful.
Now we can use this token whenever there is a need for us to access some protected roads.
So in the coming lectures we're going to learn how to protect certain roads how those roads can be accessed
by the user who have the valid took.