Now we can sign in user if there is no password or a wrong password.
We have the Vedas ultra beautiful Now what we want to do is before we move to our client side and start
building our front end.
Let's add a few more control methods such as a sign out and require sign in middleware so that we can
see how we can protect roads.
So let's create this export sign out method and get request response on sign out.
All we want to do is we want to response.
Clear cookie.
Do you remember when we generated and we added that token in the cookie again in the restaurants object
by the name of cookie but when you sign up we want to clear that from the response.
So I guess the restaurant square cookie we give the cookie name that is token.
All right.
We can send the patient response with the Mrs.
sign out census.
And finally let's also create one middleware just so that we can see how we can protect rocks will come
back to it later.
Obviously we will have all throughout our middleware admin middleware.
But at the moment let's just implement this require a sign in middle of it I guess of experts require
signing.
And we're going to use this Express JWT package we have
and all we need to do is we need to pass the secret and our secret is process dot in v dot did we do
secret.
So this is our middleware and we're going to apply this in our route.
So any road we want to protect only for the logged in users we will apply this at middleware and what
it will do is it will take the incoming tokens secret and it will compare with the secret that we have
in our Ian Lee fight and if that matters and if the token haven't expired then this will return true
and user will have access to it.
So this back is behind the scene.
It will automatically take for the token expiry so we don't need to do anything.
We just need to pass the secret.
Now with this we can go back to our out and quit road for sign out.
It's create another road just to give it a try.
See how this works.
So let's go to roads and let's create road and dirt and get this is going to be get method to sign up
sign up and sign up.
Simple as that.
We can bring that from controller I guess so this way we can sign the user out let's also create just
for test let's create a road to dot get let's say this is our secret base.
And we can drive the method here.
Request response letter response iteration
you have access to secret place.
For example let's say this is our secret base.
Only the logged in users to have access to.
So for that what we can do is we can use that middleware require signing.
So here in Rhodes we can bring that from the US controller and we can apply that as a middleware here.
So this way any rights you want to protect for only logged in you just you apply it.
So now let's go.
Let's give it a try.
First let's sign out
Let's make sign out.
Let's make it get requests.
Let's hit send and you see message sign of success.
Now let's try accessing this secret this
and you see we've got error unauthorized error no authorization token was fun because this is a particular
drought no.
So only if we have the token and invalid token then we would have access to this space.
Now let's sign in and let's send the token in the headers and let's see if we can then access this road
again.
So let's send in one more time this same information with post method and we get that token.
So what we can do is you can copy this token and we can send this token in the headers.
So here go to headers and write authorization and you put here token but make sure it is a beer token
I guess a B E R E R space and best that token then.
Now this way any request we make we are sending this token at the same time in the house.
Now let's make request to secret.
Previously we had authorized error when we tried to access this wrong.
But now with the token let's see if we can get access to and you can see misses you have access to secret
base that means when we send the token in the headers a valid token then we get access.
Beautiful.
Now if you make some turns.
Let's get rid of the first letter and let's hit send.
You see the token is invalid.
Okay.
So this is how.
So this is all you can use decent web token to implement authentication between your client application
and your API.
Now that we have implemented sign in sign up and sign out.
This is a good time for us to go to the front end and start building our an application using react.
And next this.