Before doing anything further I would like to bury the authentication system so that we can start registering
the user log them in so that they can create a new blogs and so on.
Right.
So let's work on the authentication.
The first thing we want to do is we want to create a user model and the User model will have a schema
that will tell what sort of fields will be there to create new user.
For example we might need to use a name name email the data type and is it required or not.
Things like that.
So let's go ahead and create a user model.
So here it's called a new folder let's call it models.
We're going to create user model user.
Let's start by bringing Mongoose because we're going to create a mongoose schema to contest Mongoose
equals to acquire goods.
We also need to bring crypto which is a code just module and we're going to use it to has the password
later.
So let's bring in crypto equals to require crypto.
Now let's go ahead create a you just chemical content user schema equals two new mongers dot schema
with capital S..
So this is a frontier.
And this takes the object as an argument.
So here you can write all the properties for example the user name.
When you create a user.
We're going to have a user named property right.
And we can specify the type.
So it's going to be a string type trim to any whitespace will be trimmed out required to.
So it is required if.
If we don't provide the user name then Mongols will give us an error.
Max.
Max length let's say 32 is the maximum length unique true because user names should be unique later
on we will implement the user profile system and by default we will give all the users the user name
for example domain dot com SLAs profiles SLAs user name.
So unless they update the user name we will give them some random string as the user name.
So you need to index to the index to what it will do is we will be making a lot of database queries
based on the user name.
So that's why we want to make it index symbol.
So index to lowercase to it.
So that's it for user name.
Let's copy.
Just to make things easier.
Comma paste here.
And this time let's make it name to name type will we string dream true are required to and max length
you can make name required but we're going to use validator anyway.
So let's leave it as it is.
Let's copy and paste here and let's use this for email but the type scheme to be string trimmed true
required true unique.
Make sure email is unique
maximum length 30 to maybe 12 a specified that say no.
Case to profile.
So the type is going to be stream
required to be true profile as well as the password.
We're not going to save the plain password in the database.
We're going to save the hashed version of it.
So we're going to use first password and the type is going to be strength and required truth.
And if you have worked with some other Vegas like big crypt you must have used just password not hashed
password but we're going to use crypto in this project and I recommend you to exactly follow along the
way we're doing it because it will be much easier later on again.
So do not sense the filth just continue with this one when you finish the project.
Obviously you are free to make any modification.
All right we're going to use the salt as root salt will be used to define how strong you're going to
have the password.
Salt will have some numeric value.
So we'll be generating salt as well at the moment.
We can say the normal type then we want about as well.
So our board is going to be type string then we're going to have the roll as well because really we
having it all based authentic isn't system type no dream.
Two words are going to have.
It will be the type of both begin to see a photo in the binary data format in the database and among
the is perfect for saving binary data for the will have the content type as well.
And that's going to be a script.
So it's going to be something like emits less Bindi you miss less Zbig and so on.
And finally we're going to also use a reset password link.
I guess we'll be using this much later in the course we will be implementing the forward password and
reset password functionality so at that time we will generate a token and save in the database and then
we will email that token to the user when they click on that link.
They'll be redirected to the react application and then from their react app will send the token back
to our server and then we're going to check if that token is exactly the one we have in the database
again.
Now it can be confusing at the moment but onward we will go through that in depth so you'll get complete
understanding.
But at the moment just a bit here reset password link.
This is going to be a double the type of string and then by default it will be empty.
This is how you the schema we have username name email profile hast password sold about droll photo
and reset password link
finally let's also add timestamp timestamp.
We're not going to add here.
Instead we're going to pass here.
So as you can see this is a mongo schema.
So this is the first I admit.
The entire object.
And then the second argument here the timestamp timestamp.
And we set truth to this we wouldn't need to create ourself manually it will automatically and created
an updated date in the database with all that we done with our schema.
So what we can do is we can module or exports equals to Mongols store model.
So what are we going to call this model.
We're going to call user with capital.
You okay.
This is convention to indicate that this is a user model and then user schema so this is our Mongo schema
for user more.
Now we can use this user model to create a new user and save saving the database but there is a bit
more to do here because we will be getting the plain password and we need to save as has password just
realized that it shouldn't be just Max no length this max and it should be all law guess it sort of
made that teens let's make it Max
all lowercase
and that is it.
So we're going to do some more here in the following lecture.