To create a new user we need to set up roots and controls.
So let's begin with road.
Let's go drought folder.
And we can pretty much copy this code just to make things easier.
And let's create a new file called out dirt to.
And it's based here to create a new user we can call that sign up any request coming to this sign up.
We can handle using the sign up method and control so we can create this method in control of control
and we can use that here.
So this is our roads.
Let's not forget to bring this in server just like we did earlier from blogs.
Auto roads from roads out and we can use that as a middleware
arthropods again.
So we have the roads.
Now let's go ahead and create what controllers see here.
It's called a new fire let's call it authorities and we need to create this sign up method right.
So let's go ahead export sign up
to create a new user.
We need the user name email it password and we will get that information from the request body.
So at the moment we'll be using postman.
And later we will be using react.
So either way we need to send this in person in the request body so that we can create a new user.
So let's destructor this information for request boarding.
So we need name email and password
just to give it a try.
Let's respond with the same information.
Let's send it back to the user.
Just to give it a try.
Before we saving the database.
Hey so restaurants that are invitation so we send the JSON response with the name of user.
That's going to be the key and the value is going to be name email and password let's try it out.
Let's good to postman let's make a post request.
So this has to be post and the URL is going to be his TGP is Collins less less local host.
Eight thousand SLAs API SLAs sign up.
Now we need to go to the body because we need to send the body the request body.
All right.
So here click on Raw and select the data and decent application.
Jason right now we can work this out here.
Name one
email.
Ryan at GMU dot com.
Password
that's just wrote right password.
Now we can send this information to our backing to create a new user name before we do that.
We need to make sure we need to go to Harris and make sure the content type is application decent.
Make sure you have distinct.
Let's give it a try let's hit send again.
We didn't get in response.
Let's have a look here.
So this has to be pushed again.
We're posting the data so make sure you have this post not get and this has to be his TTP not.
S All right let's give it a try.
And as you can see the same information we send to the back end is sent back to us as a decent response.
Now what do we need to do is instead of sending the information back to ourself we need to said this
in missing in the database so we can start creating new users and send them in the database.