Before we say users in the database we need to do a couple of takes such as validation.
We need to make sure that name email and password fields are required.
E-mail should be type of email password should be at least six characters long and things like that.
So that is validation.
Next we need to has the password before we send in the database.
And then third we need to make sure that user with the same email does not already exist in the database.
So we need to make some checks before we are able to send a user in the database.
So the first thing we need to do is install some NBN packages and then install express validate or young
to use X was validated for validation and then we need decent web token to generate decent web tokens
so that we can send that to our client whether it's postman or react.
And that will allow us to implement authentication and get and then express did WD Tea Baggers as well.
So this will take if the generated token is still valid or not.
And we are also going to use a package called Formidable.
This will allow us to receive farm data because we will be sending farm data from the client side to
the service side.
So that is different than a decent data type that is a phone data type so to Hammond that we need.
This bag is formidable.
We need Lord less as well.
So we're going to use shoe helper methods from Lotus library and we need a few more packages for saving
our blog in the database.
So let's install them Azra slug Fi and string death strip Das has to email.
Okay so this package packages will be used to create a new blog.
Let me hit enter.
So while it's happening let me show you why we need sluggish flight.
So if you go to visit any base because our biggest one will be ACL.
So let's say let's go to current dot com.
Just to give it a try.
So for example you can see this is the blog title right.
So if you click here you see we have the domain names.
Less articles SLAs the blog title and it is all lowercase and it has the deaths.
Whenever there is space has been replaced with death and all of them have been logged kiss again.
So this is his slug.
So we need to generate slow for each blog post we said in the database and then we will query the database
based on the slope we are going to use 80 in most of the time you see something like this when most
of the tutorials you see articles less idea and we find the blogs based on the 80 but that would not
be issue and this is not a good user experience as well.
Okay so we're going to generate such slugs and for that reason we had this beggars in stone slug slump
and then we have this string strip estimate.
So what did we do is when you create a new blog for example this is the starting few lines of your blog.
So these few lines the first few lines we can take them to generate a meta description again that is
extremely important for issue.
So if you go to view page source you see this base has this title.
So the domain name and then the blog title he initiated the title.
You can see met a description I guess that this has Tim in and you see in this journey you learn to
properly set up next this front end and so on.
So these first few 160 characters have been extracted from the blog body automatically saved in the
database as a meta description that way when you render your blog they will have met a description as
well.
So very well ready for search engine optimization.