To implement a user sign up the first thing we need to do is we need to validate for example when the
user sending data like a name email and password.
We need to run some validation that really tick.
If the password has at least six characters if a name is there it's not empty.
If the email is a valid email right.
So we need to perform those checks.
So let's begin by creating a validated method so that we can use that validator in our route.
So when we are signing up the user we get requests on this end point and then we run some validation
here and then if that value doesn't pass only then we will execute this control method.
So to create a validator we can create a separate folder let's call it validator validators.
And here we need to create a file called index start.
This
and let us also create a file for what it is.
So here we going to put all authentication related validations again.
So first let's bring in check form.
Require
express validator.
Okay.
And then we can write a check.
So we're going to export it so that we're going to use it root.
So exports.
User Sino validator.
And this is going to be an array thank you.
So here we can write whatever we want to check.
For example we want to check the name tag and first we want to check the name again not is empty.
So we want to make sure there is name and it is not empty.
And if it is empty we will send the message with Mrs. name is name is required.
Okay.
So this are we check the name.
Now let's copy and make sure you have comma here and let's pasted down here.
Now this one we can use for email.
So email also we want to.
Let's make sure this is the type of email.
So is email.
So this will take if the data we are receiving is the type of email your name at email dot com that
structure it will text or you don't need to write really explicit here with this one.
So is email.
And if not we send the message.
But it must be a valid email address.
And we also want to validate passwords so let's copy one more time.
Make sure you add comma here.
Based here and this time we take for password and we want to make sure it has at least six characters.
I guess so is length here we say minimum six and with Mrs.
password must be at least six six characters.
OK.
So this is all a sign of validator.
So this is our validator is a sign of value.
Now when this value did it runs.
If we don't get the name email a password anything like that.
So this these messages will be sent as an error.
So how do we send the error.
We can read that here in the index.
And the reason I'm writing here is because later we will have many valid there just for example either
days of a blog there will be quite a few but you don't have to keep writing the same errors look.
So we just write here and we can reuse this.
So let's write here const we can grab the validation result validation result from require Express and
validation again.
So if there were any errors doing this take we will get them here again so we can export let's call
it a run validation.
And because this is a middle way we need.
Request response.
And next.
So next is a callback function I get to hear.
Plus we get errors from validation result and we pass the request.
So we'll be getting the request a name email and password in the request and then we take here.
If no errors dot is empty.
So if errors is not empty that means we have an error.
Right.
So if you have an error we want to return that error.
So return response with status of four twenty two.
Jason error.
And that's going to be errors.
Don't go away if we get the error sorry but we want to send only the first one to this we wouldn't have
to look through errors in the front end which can be really annoying.
So as soon as there is any error we give that error the very first one and then we just say messes.
We want to send the very first error messes with the status quo to find a at 22 which is I think it's
a UN process about entity.
I guess once you do that we want to execute this callback next so that our application doesn't get hot.
So this way you write a middleware.
Now we can use this in rafts.
So let's cut roads and let's bring those validated.
You
can't run from validation from required
validators because it is an index or just value the need to write anything you just say validate us.
And we also need sign of validation.
So it's right here.
The user sign a valid ID.
Make sure this is the right name with a sign of validation.
And I get from validators SLAs.
OK.
So now that we have our villages we can apply here as a middleware.
First you say you just had a valid ID.
Then we run validation.
So if the validation is passed on then the code in the sign up control method will be executed.
Okay.
So once we have applied all this we can give it a try.
Just to make sure that validation is working.
Okay.
So let's try making a request without name I.D. you get the error name is required.
Burak if you remove the ad from the email sent must be a valid image Everest.
Beautiful.
And if you give your password less than six characters you get password must be at least six again.
So our validation is working beautifully.
Now we can continue for the.