So to sign up user frosting we had to do was valid isn't and we did that in the last setting.
Now in this section we're going to implement the passwords to hassling of the password.
Okay.
So let's begin.
That's good to our models.
We're going to write this in our user model.
So on this schema for example in our case we have the user schema.
So in this user schema we can add methods and we can even use something called a virtual field.
Okay.
So what is virtual is that for example we want to get password from the client side however we want
to save the has to password.
We don't want to say anything as password in the database.
I get so virtual fields just exist that it doesn't get persisted in the database but in exist there.
So that we can do some work.
So in our case we get to grab the password from the client and has that blend password and saving the
database as has the password.
Okay.
So here you just Kim and Dot virtual here.
The virtual field is going to be password like.
And then here let me bring it down just a bit.
So the virtual field password we're going to use two methods set and get again.
So we're going to set we're going to use a function and make sure you use the regular function not the
error function again because error phones don't have their own scope for this cure.
So that will not work.
So make sure you use the regular function so function password
and we going to sort of create a temporary variable called the school password.
Then what are we going to do is we're going to generate a generate salt.
It'll be used for a hashing algorithm.
So once you do that we will need to encrypt password again.
So first let's do here.
This dot underscore password equals to password this salt equals to this dot makes salt.
So we don't have this method yet we're going to create soon that will generate the salt again.
So we need to create this method makes salt encrypt the password.
We're going to take this test password and we're going to populate its value with the highest version.
And I guess this dirt encrypt password we're going to create this method as well.
And we're going to pass the plain password and this will has the password and save that value in the
hash password.
And this is what's going to be saved in the database.
So this is how we're going to set.
And then we have this gift until we need it from some.
And this will return this dirt underscore password so we need to create these two methods mix salt and
encrypt password.
So on this user schema we can create methods and add to it.
Using this in the schema dot method methods equals two we create an object.
And here we're going to create these functions and we need to separate them with the common.
So first one let's call it encrypt password.
That's the one we need to make sure to use the regular function is a function password.
First of all we're going to take if we're not getting any password from the client then we want to just
we can't do anything we just written empty string.
I get.
And then we try and then we get any air.
If there is an error we just reach an empty street.
So what do you want to do is we want to try to have the password to plain password.
So we're going to use the script book that comes with an A.D. by default.
So return crypto.
And we have a couple of methods available with this with this module.
So crypto dart create Tate's Mac.
Now all this is also in the north.
This official website so you can also go there if you're interested in this crypto module.
But I'm just going to type it down here and you can also grab this quote from the source code.
If you find it a bit difficult to type.
So the housing algorithm we're going to use is assets a what.
So that's the first argument and the sec second argument is going to be this dot salt.
Then we get another method of date and update the password and then digest takes.
So this is encrypt password method.
Now we need another method called make salt.
So right here.
Make sure you have comma.
And then let's create this method as well.
Make salt from some and we going to return math dot around going to use new date
value of.
Multiply by math dot random plus trip.
So this will give us some random numerical value that we can use here when we have seen the password.
So we have got two methods here into password and make salt.
We also need one more method during the user sign in process.
So while we're here let's write that down so that we don't have to come back again again.
So that is going to be authenticate.
So we're going to use this method to authenticate the user.
So basically what are you going to do is we're going to compare the password.
So when we get the plain password from the client we're going to take that and encrypt that plain password
and compare with the hash to version of it which we have in the database.
And if they've met that means we can't authenticate that user because their password mats.
Right.
So this should be used during the user signing.
So this is also going to be a function
plain text or plain password.
We're going to get from the user.
OK.
Let's not forget to add a comma here.
All right.
So we're going to return.
It's going to return the value that is going to be the true or false I guess.
This encrypt password plaintext.
So we're going to has this password that is coming from the client type.
And we're going to compare using this tool equal operator.
This dot has a password.
So when we compare we will get either true or false.
So if it is true then the user will be authenticated.
Otherwise they will not be authenticated.
So this is it.
So we have a schema.
We have the virtual field to handle the password and save as has the password.
And then we have these few methods in the year just Kim.
One is to authenticate to compare the password.
Another is to has the password.
And another is to generate soft again.
So with all this we've pretty much done with the user schema.
Now we can go ahead in the next lecture create a new user and save in the database.
That means we will be walking in the control in the next lecture.