Let's go ahead and sign up a user so that we can send the user in the database.
But before we do that you must have not forgot that our users will have the user name I guess.
So that will be automatically generated when they sign up for the first one I get.
So to generate a unique user names we're going to use a package called a sharp I.D..
So let's install npm install sought deep
let's start the server once again let's import that.
Here comes first of all let's bring the user content user equals to require
models SLAs user cost site I.D. which capital I equals to require Sadat now to save the user the very
first thing we need to do is we need to take if the user already exists.
So if this user who is trying to sign up if that email is already in the database to identify the uniqueness
it gets through if that user with that email already exist then who cannot sign up again.
Right.
So first minute tick.
So let's get rid of this for now.
Well we took using user dot find one.
So we get this find one method with mongers that will help us find a particular user from the database.
So in this case we're going to find based on email.
So e-mail and the value that we're going to get that from request dot boarding dot e-mail.
So we're going to find the user based on e-mail and then the email we'll be getting is from the request
board.
So once we do that we can use this execute method that gets to this is a method that comes with Mongoose.
So this X good method takes a function as an argument I guess so we're going to use our phones in here.
So in this function we get either error or user.
So when this method runs that will either find the user if it doesn't find the user then it will give
us the error.
So here first we need to handle the error first.
Let's take for user.
So if user then we need to send the error message that sorry the e-mail is taken.
All right.
So if user if we found the user we're going to return with this status of 400 and the decent restaurants
we're going to send by the name of error and the value is going to be let's say e-mail is thinking if
the user doesn't already exist then we can go ahead and create a new user.
Right.
So to create a new user we need name email password which comes from the client side in addition to
that we need to generate the user name as well as profile.
So if you go have a look in the User model User Name Name Email profile you see it's going to be the
url.
So what we can do here is to create a new user first all let's grab the name email password from the
request body you name email password and I'm using the object restructuring here.
Let me use the name equals to.
We're going to use that I added Peggy's sharp I.D. capitalized and it has this method called generate
E2 that would generate a unique sharp I.D. I guess so that is going to be the user name.
Now let's create a profile as well.
Now the profile is going to be whatever the domain name of how client side application for example it
might be issue blog Dot com.
So that is going to be the URL followed by profile SLAs the user name.
So little profile.
We need the client to area.
So let's have a look in the E envy if we have one.
Yes we have beautiful.
Thank you.
So we can use this
select profile.
Now I'm going to use back ticks because I need to embed some variables you see dollar sign embrace and
here I'm going to write code to start in the DART client yard.
So that will give me the client here.
Now to generate a profile you Earl I'm going to use that SLAs profile SLAs user name.
Again dollar sign user name.
Okay.
So this is how we generate the profile are as well.
Now we can create a new user let's call it.
Let new user equals to new user new user more new instance.
And we pass the argument name email password profile his name and then we can send this user to new
user dirt.
Same I.
So when we say
to take whether it has been successfully simple.
So there are success.
So first of all we always need to make sure we check the error.
We handle the error properly so if error region response with a status of four hundred Dirk and Jason
we give the error message error.
Otherwise we return with the distant response I get to now here what do we can do is we can actually
send the user where has been just created.
We can send his user name email and so on but that is not really important because this is just a sign
of process.
So all we need to do is we need to send a message saying that okay you have sent off successfully.
So let's send messages with the value of let's say of success please sign it.
So this way we can sign up a new user possibly find if any user exist or we give this error message.
Otherwise we create new user.
We save that user and we handle the error if there is any.
Otherwise we respond with this misses.
But just for now let me just comment this out and let me actually respond with the actual user that
has been created I guess just from the end user that scheme to be a success.
So whatever we get here we can return that let's give it a try.
It looks like something's gone cannot find modules to user like we need to go one step of models and
end user.
Beautiful.
All right let's give it a try.
Let's try signing up without name.
That works.
Beautiful.
Now let's pass everything right.
Name Email and password and let's try creating this user.
It's it's in okay.
So we've got this huge error object.
Okay.
After some debugging and some console lost everything was working fine.
The issue was in our user model.
So in our user model we have salt and that is the type number I have given.
So it should be straight.
Okay.
So with no it doesn't seem to work.
So make this tent and then if we give it a try it should work.
Now let's try and you see we get the newly created user here.
We can also have a look in the database.
So if you have Robert through the installed he can open that and let's go to our database and then click
on clicks and see users.
And here we have a newly created user like you see the user name is automatically generated password
is has a profile has been created.
Beautiful right.
So if you are using Mongo Atlas then you should be able to see the data like that in a similar way we
should be able to access your database visually and even modify I guess to maybe we should give that
a try as well.
But before we do that let me come back here in our control and sign up.
We don't want to respond with the user data because it doesn't have any use case.
So I'm going to just comment it out again and then just bring this back in.
So the next time you sign up we will give them this message.
Same success please sign it.
All right.
So let's give it a try with Mongo Atlas as well.