Those of you who are using Mongo Atlas and those who are new to it and want to see how they can browse
through the endless decimal I get.
So let me quickly.
Good to talk to Ian v
let me grab the data this cloud and then go back to my subject this year and temporarily I'm going to
freeze this to of his clout.
And I'm going to restart the server just to make sure everything is right.
After a while we should see no
again network failed connect server.
Now let's see if that works.
Let's give it a try
again now we're talking on how it started working I didn't think I've made things here maybe it was
because I white listed all the IP address including my what.
So hopefully it doesn't have to go through this trouble but sometimes it just seems to be unavoidable
with Mongo Atlas.
Unfortunately hopefully you were able to open right now.
Let's give it a try.
One last time.
So this user said in the local database so we should be able to run it one more time and sign of success
please.
That means we should have a new user created in here.
Let's give it a try.
It's good to collections
and.
Right this way you are able to see the data visually in one would do with Atlas Haswell.